# Naman Satiya

### Data Enthusiast, Critical Thinker, Avid Reader, Paraglider, Numismatist

Durham, NC 27705 namansatiyazgzv5\_tqn@indeedemail.com +1 984 888 4374

A specialized generalist with a strong focus on delivering value and a strong bias for actionable insights. Have one foot in data, and the other everywhere across the organization.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

#### Work Experience

### **Datathon: Medical Appointment no-shows | Best Data Analysis Award**

Data Club, Duke University

November 2021 to November 2021

- Performed Exploratory Data Analysis and trained a Random Forest model to find the characteristics of medical patients who tend to miss out on their doctor appointments in a 30hr competition, with an F1-score of 0.79.
- Assessed the problem of a skewed dataset (20%) by generating four derived features and finding recall-precision balance based on the Cost-Function.

# Kaggle: Classical Music Meets Classical ML

**Duke University** 

September 2021 to November 2021

- Trained and implemented an ensemble model to predict customers who will buy subscription tickets to next year's orchestra performance, with AUROC = 0.97.
- Utilized Logistic Regression, Random Forest, KNN, and Decision Trees to train the model and reinforce with

Confusion Matrix, Cross-Validation, and Hyperparameter tuning to improve results by 18% over baseline.

#### **Customer Segmentation - Grocery Store**

**Duke University** 

September 2021 to November 2021

- Manipulated 27-feature grocery store data to find customer characteristic insights with the highest sale value, using Logistic Regression with an accuracy score of 0.86 to identify a new segment with 22% higher spending.
- Proposed a marketing plan with coupons and offers for a potential boost of 11% in total revenue.

#### iWear - Business Idea Award

Data Club, Duke University

August 2021 to November 2021

• Developed a business model for an Al-based app that assists everyone in finding the perfect fitting shoe with just two photos, using market analysis and strategy comparison.

• Generated a wireframe, determined the algorithm and database requirements, assumed the role of Chief Vision

Officer, and pitched the idea in the competition.

#### **Engineering Associate**

Johnson Controls (India) Pvt Ltd. - Mumbai, Maharashtra October 2018 to May 2021

- Engineered algorithms to configure HVAC equipment for 150+ projects in the northeastern US, including major hospitals, university buildings, airports, and corporate spaces using Function Block (FB) programming.
- Programmed database and supervisory level logic for smooth communication between systems, produced trends, and created pop-up alarms to assist easy debugging for customers.
- Created 4 Excel VB scripts to automate repetitive tasks, saving 40+ hours among four different projects.
- Assisted project leads in reviewing 50+ new projects and developing 'Query Sheets', reducing  $\sim$ 30% re-work.
- Conducted 2 Kaizen trainings, evaluated 100+ idea submissions, and assisted in implementing 6 ideas as a core member of the Kaizen Innovation Team.

#### **Analyst Intern**

Robert Bosch Engineering & Business Solutions Limited. - Bengaluru, Karnataka June 2017 to July 2017

- Built algorithms for data preprocessing, filtration, and bench-marking electrical machines to develop 'Integrated Energy Platform' reducing data gaps by 12%.
- Developed customizable turnkey modules to evaluate outliers, pinpoint electrical anomalies, and create visualizations of the most critical parameters.

#### Education

# Master of Engineering Management in Data Analytics and Machine Learning track

Duke University - Durham, NC August 2021 to December 2022

#### Skills

- Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn)
- Excel (VBScript, Pivot, Macros)
- Jupyter
- Statistics Data Concept:Machine Learning
- · Causal Inference
- · AB Testing
- PCA
- EDA
- Predictive Analytics

• Regression Data Visualization: Tableau

Excel

• PowerPoint Database Language: MySQL

- SQL Server
- Business Analysis
- SQL
- Regression Analysis
- Data Modeling
- VBA (1 year)

## Links

http://linkedin.com/in/satiyanaman